Inspired by the actual files of Father Gabriele
Amorth, Chief Exorcist of the Vatican.
The Pope's Exorcist is a horror, thriller film directed by Julius Avery.
Father Gabriele Amorth, Chief Exorcist of the Vatican, investigates a young boy's terrifying possession and
ends up uncovering a centuries-old conspiracy the Vatican has desperately tried to keep hidden.
Father Gabriele Amorth, played by Russell Crowe.
Father Esquibel, played by Daniel Zovatto.
Julia, played by Alex Essoe.
Henry, played by Peter DeSouza-Feighoney.
Asmodeus (voice), played by Ralph Ineson.
Amy, played by Laurel Marsden.
The Pope's Exorcist is a 2023 supernatural horror film directed by Julius Avery from a screenplay by Michael Petroni and Evan
Spiliotopoulos, based on the 1990 book An Exorcist Tells His Story and the 1992 book An Exorcist: More Stories by Father Gabriele Amorth.
The film stars Russell Crowe as Amorth, with Daniel Zovatto,
Alex Essoe, and Franco Nero in supporting roles.
Production began in 2020 when Screen Gems
purchased the rights to Amorth's story.
After a directorial replacement and script revisions, filming
occurred in Ireland from August to October 2022.
The Pope's Exorcist was released in several  countries beginning on
April 5, 2023, and in the United States on April 14.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $77 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of spain, rome, italy, pig, vatican (holy see), pope.
The tone is dark and intense.